In the last video,
I introduced the concept of
continuous improvements.
We explored in depth
how working in
a controlled environment
can optimize your outcomes.
In this video, we're
going to keep on
that same path of uncovering
methods for continuous
improvements.
We'll start with data-driven
improvement frameworks.
Data-driven improvement
frameworks are techniques
used to make decisions
based on actual data.
The first data-driven improvement
framework we'll cover
may be familiar to you since
we discussed it in
a previous course.
Recall that D-M-A-I-C, or DMAIC,
stands for define, measure,
analyze, improve, and
control, and it maps
out five steps that you can
take when working toward
continuous improvements.
When considering how you
can improve customer experiences,
start with the following:
First, you'll need to define
the business problem, goals,
resources, project scope,
and project timeline.
Next, measure.
Here, you'll conduct
performance metrics and data
collection to establish
baselines and measure success.
Then, analyze. Work to find
the root causes of problems
and understand their impact.
Next, improve.
This means implementing
a reasonable solution
to the problem.
Lastly, control.
This is where you'll implement
the changes and stay on top of
monitoring the updated
processes you've established.
Another framework you can
refer to when working through
continuous improvements is PDCA.
PDCA is a four-step process
that focuses on
identifying a problem,
fixing that issue, assessing
whether the fix was
successful, and fine-tuning
the final fix.
The steps are as
follows: First, plan.
Here, you'll identify
the issue and
root cause and brainstorm
solutions to the problem.
Let's say that one type of
plant isn't selling well,
which means the warehouse is
full of a particular species.
If you don't do something fast,
the plants may die soon.
What are some viable solutions?
You propose moving the
items from the bottom
of the sales page on
the website to the top so
those plants are
front and center.
You could also send out
email marketing campaigns
featuring that plant, where you
offer customers a buy one,
get one offer on the plant.
Second, do, or fix the problem.
In this case, your sponsor
decided that they didn't
feel comfortable giving plants
away if they could still profit.
You've decided to go
with the first option:
moving the plant to a more
prominent part of the website.
Your hypothesis is that
the best way to shift
older inventory is to put it in
a place that
customers can't miss.
The next part of this
framework is check.
Compare your results to the goal
to find out if the
problem is fixed.
Now you wait one
week and notice if
the sales numbers go up for
that plant. If they did,
your hypothesis is
correct and you've saved
some plant lives and helped
Office Green avoid
financial loss.
Nice job! Finally, act,
or fine-tune the fix to ensure
continuous improvement.
In our example, you decide
to reorganize the website.
In the future, all
overstocked plants
will get a prominent
place on the website.
Both PDCA and DMAIC are
great problem-solving
frameworks to apply in
your day-to-day life
and in the workplace.
These frameworks help
you to identify issues,
reduce errors, and
optimize your processes.
I encourage you to think about
these techniques next
time you encounter
a problem or notice room for
improvement within a workflow.
You'll be surprised at how
a simple framework can help
set you up for success.
Awesome! Now you know more about
advocating for and creating
continuous improvements.
We also defined and went
through some examples of using
frameworks DMAIC and PDCA
for process improvements.
Now that you know the basics of
continuous improvement
and process improvement,
we'll discuss the
differences between
projects and programs
and how they intersect.
I'll meet you in the next video.